A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Auxiliary Services, Published Works using materials from the RU archives FA851
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, Auxiliary Services, Published Works using materials from the RU archives
1912-1990
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
New York University
Rockefeller University
Cornell University
Cornell University. Medical College
FA851
1 Cubic Feet 2 boxes and one oversized item.
2 boxes and one oversized item.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 895
Conditions Governing Access note
This collection is open for research.
Medical research; Medical education; Women; Science -- Study and teaching; Architecture; Medicine, Preventive; Biochemistry; Biology -- Research; Women’s history; Life sciences; Cell and biomolecular sciences; Medical sciences; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research; New York University; Rockefeller University; Cornell University; Cornell University. Medical College
- M. Sluyser, "De ontdekking van DNA" Natur en techniek. 49⁶ jaargang. (April 1981), 280-299, 1981 April (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes photographs of Oswald T. Avery, p. 286, and laboratory of P.A. Levene, pp. 295-296.
- R.J.M. Butzelaar, Het bedreigde been amputatie of vaatreconstructie een na-onderzoek over 5 tot 10 jaar. 1981. Drukkerij Van Gorcum Assen. Omslag: Maarten Breuker (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Includes photograph of Alexis Carrel, p. 4.
- John Hatcher, "Simon Flexner, " The Gazette of the Institute of Medical Laboratory Sciences 25 (August 1981) pp. 317-318, 1981 August (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Includes photograph of Simon Flexner, p. 317.
- A. McGehee Harvey, M.D., "Francis Weld Peabody: The blending of general Internal medicine and clinical science" The Pharos 44 (Summer 1981) pp. 6-8 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Includes photograph of the Hospital. staff, 1912.
- Philip J. Pauly, "Jacques Loeb and the Control of Life: An Experimental Biologist in Germany and America, 1859-1924" copyright 1980, The Johns Hopkins University Ph. D. 1981; see especially Chapter X, "The Temple of Pure Science: Loeb at The Rockefeller Institute, 1910-1924" pp. 237-283, 1854-1924 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  [Library has copy of dissertation; photocopy of Chapter X in this file].
- A. McGehee Harvey, M.D. Research and Discovery in Medicine. Contributions from Johns Hopkins (Baltimore and London: The Johns Hopkins University Press, copyright 1981), 1912 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Includes photograph of the Hospital staff, 1912, page 254.
- Elmer Bendiner, "Past and Present. Heidelberger at 95, Still 'Pig-headedly' Productive" Hospital Practice 18: 214-215, 220-22, 226-27, 230-34 (October 1983), 1923 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Includes photograph of the Hospital Staff, 1923, p. 227.
- Christopher Gray. "The More Stately Mansions of Madison Avenue" AVENUE, Vol. 8, No 1 (September 1983) 59-69, 1983 September (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Includes photograph of Christian A. Herter. Photograph by G.C. Cox, page 65.
- Elmer Bendiner, "Past HOSPITAL PRACTICE 19 (February 1984) 222-223, 227, 231, 234-236, 238, 242-243, 246-247, 250, 254-255 and Present. Noguchi: Many Triumphs and a Brilliant Failure", 1984 February (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Includes photographs of Noguchi, H. p. 223
  p. 235 Noguchi extracting a sample of snake venom at medical school in Bahia, Brazil.
  p. 243. Noguchi chatting with Frederick G. Banting (shortly after the discovery of insulin at RI.
  p. 247. 1927 Noguchi in an open surfboat landing at Accra.
  p. 255 Noguchi is shown dissecting a monkey in Accra with Alexander Mahaffy looking on.
- "In Memoriam. Stanley W. Sajdera 1939-1975" by "DDD". Program for Gordon Research Conference on Proteoglycans. Plymouth State College (N), Plymouth, New Hampshire. June 11-15, 1984. Chairman: Klaus Kuettner, Ph. D. Vice- Chairman: Vincent Hascall, Ph. D. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Includes photograph of Stanley Sajdera from RU Archives.
- Christopher Gray. "The River's Rustic Charm Gives Way to Commerce" AVENUE (June-July-August 1984) 68-77, 1984 June-August (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Includes photograph of Boxers, Pastime Athletic Club, ca 1900. [See also 412 (3) 1].
  See also: Directory of Graduates (New York: The Rockefeller University, 1984). RG 600-15 25th anniversary of graduates.
- Ward, Patricia Spain, "The Other Abraham: Flexner in Illinois". In: Caduceus 2 (Spring 1986) pp 1-69 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  [includes] photograph of A. Flexner from Rockefeller University Archives opposite page 1. See also: S. Flexner papers RG 301. 6, Box 3, for publication.
- Koch, Sabine, re Erdmann, Rhoda: Leben und Werk der Zellforscherin Rhoda Erdmann (1870-1935). Inaugural-Dissertation zur Erlangung des Doktorgrades der gesamten Medizin. Dem Fachbereich Humanmedizin der Philipps-Universität Marburg vorgelegt von Sabine Koch aus Friedberg in Hessen, Marburg 1985. Aus dem Institut für Geschichte der Medizin in Marburg. Direktor: Prof. Dr. Hans H. Lauer (Box 1, Folder 12)
- "Alfred Ogle Shaklee" in Descendants of Peter Shaklee (1756-1834), William E. Shaklee, ed., Vol. VI, No. 3, September 1986, pp. 33-34 (to be continued), 1986 December (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Added 12/86, Vol. VI, No. 4, December 1986, pp. 40-43.
  Given to Mrs. Mirsky for RUL[?],23 October 1986.
- Edward O. Dodson and Peter Dodson, Evolution: Process and Product (Boston: Prindle, Weber, and Schmidt, 1985). 3rd edition. RUA Photo of T. Dobzhansky, p. 117 (Box 1)
- Robert H. Tamarin, Principles of Genetics. 2nd edition (Boston: Prindle, Weber, and Schmidt, 1986). RUA photo of Peyton Rous, p. 570 (Box 1)
- Reprint. Lily E. Kay, "W.M. Stanley's Crystallization of the Tobacco Mosaic Virus, 1930-1940" Isis 77: 450-472 (1986) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Immediate Source of Acquisition note
  From Lily E. Kay, received 5 December 1986.
- Reprint. Steven J. Peitzman, M.D., "Nephrology in the United States from Osler to the Artificial Kidney" Annals of Internal Medicine (December 1986) 105: 937-946, 1986 December (Box 1, Folder 15)
  RUA photo of D.D. Van Slyke.
  From Steven J. Peitzman, M.D., received 30 January 1987.
- Jamie Talan, "The Bacteria War" Newsday, 1990 January 30 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Witkowski, J.A. "Alexis Carrel and the Mysticism of Tissue Culture" Medical History. 1979, 23: 279-296 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Witkowski, J.A. "Dr. Carrel's Immortal Cells" Medical History. 1980, 24: 129-142 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Rosof, Patricia J.F. "Explaining Success: The Career of Dr. Florence Rena Sabin" (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Talk presented at Southern Association for the History of Medicine and Science meeting 2006.
- Jeffrey L. Cruikshank, A Delicate Experiment: The Harvard Business School,1908-1945. (Boston, Massachusetts: Harvard Business School Press, 1987), [oversize]
  RUA photo of Jerome D. Greene, p. 86.
  Publication using material from the archives.
  From Joanne F. Segal, received February 6, 1987.
  File Plan note
  Former Classification: I.895